（サスケ）ハハハハハッ！
どうだ　こいつが→
How's this?
So can your borrowed Sharingan
extinguish that?!
お前の借り物の写輪眼で
消せるか！？
本物と借り物の差ってやつを
見せつけてやるぜ！
I will show you the difference
between the real thing
and a fake!
Damn it!
クソッ！
《し…　視界が！》
My sight!
《カカシ：サクラ　何で出てきた！？》
Sakura! Why are you here?
よせ！
Don't!
I won't let Kakashi Sensei
bear the burden!
《サクラ：カカシ先生に
重荷は背負わせない！》
((俺は　お前たちとは違う。
I'm different from you guys.
お前たちとは
相容れない道にいる。
I'm walking a road that's
incompatible with the rest of you.
４人でやってきた。
The four of us worked together...
確かに　それを自分の道と
思おうとしたこともある。
and it's true that
there was a time
when I thought that
was my road.
４人でやってきたが
俺の心は　結局　復讐を決めた。
The four of us have
worked together,
but in the end,
I decided on revenge.
俺は　そのために生きてきた！
That's been my reason
for living.
俺は　お前や
ナルトのようにはなれない！
I can't be like you or Naruto.
私　サスケ君のためなら
なんだってする！
I'll do anything for you, Sasuke!
だから
お願いだからここにいて！
So...I'm begging you,
please stay here!
復讐だって手伝う！
I'll even help you
with your revenge!
絶対　私が
なんとかしてみせるから！
I'll make it happen somehow,
I promise you!
だから　ここに→
So stay here with me!
私と一緒に…。
If that doesn't work for you,
then take me with you.
それが　ダメなら
私も一緒に連れてって。
やっぱり　お前　うざいよ。
You really are…annoying.
行かないで！
Don't go!
If you go, I'll scream and…
行くなら　私
大声出してでも…。
サクラ…。
Sakura…
(ありがとう))
Thank you.
サクラ！
Sakura!
Stop, Sasuke!
よせ！　サスケ！
Two Fates
俺以上に　いいタイミングだよ　ナルト。
Your timing is better
than mine, Naruto.
お前まで来ちゃうとは
思わなかったけど。
I never imagined you coming here.
You're a lifesaver!
とにかく　助かったよ。
ありがとう　ナルト。
Th-Thank you, Naruto.
《サスケ君　本当に私を殺そうとした。
Sasuke really tried to kill me.
ナルトがいなければ
今頃　私は殺されていた。
If Naruto hadn't come,
I would be dead now.
サスケ君の手で…》
By Sasuke's own hand.
（ナルト）サスケ　サクラちゃんは同じ
第七班のメンバーだぞ。
Sasuke…
Sakura is a fellow ninja
from Team 7.
元　第七班だ　俺はな…。
"Was" a fellow ninja.
I no longer belong.
今ので　わかっただろ。
Now do you understand,
Naruto, Sakura?
ナルト　サクラ　ヤツに宿っていたのは
本当の殺気だ。
His intent to kill is real.
サスケは　もう
昔のサスケじゃなくなってる。
Sasuke is no longer
the same person as before.
サスケ。
何だ？
Sasuke…
What?
イタチの真実ってのを→
I heard the truth about Itachi
from a guy named Tobi.
トビってヤツから聞いた。
《イタチの真実？》
The truth about Itachi?
俺には　アイツの言ったことが
嘘か本当かは　よくわからねえ。
I don't know for sure
if what he said is really true or not.
けど　どっちにしても
お前のやってることは→
But it doesn't matter.
What you've been doing is…
わかるってばよ。
understandable.
ナルト　前に言ったはずだ。
Naruto… I told you before.
親も兄弟もいねえテメエに→
You don't have parents or siblings,
so you couldn't possibly understand me.
俺の何がわかるってな…。
他人は黙ってろ！
So outsiders can keep
their mouths shut!
ナルトがどんな思いでサスケ君を…。
Do you know what Naruto
has gone through for you?
どんな悪い噂を耳にしても→
No matter what rumors
we hear about you,
ずっと仲間だと思ってた。
he never stops thinking
of you as a friend.
みんながサスケ君を狙っても→
While everyone targeted you,
ナルトだけは　ずっとサスケ君を
助けようと思ってる。
Naruto alone tried to rescue you!
今だって…。
Even now…
俺を助けるだと？
Rescue me? From what?
何から？
それは…。
Well, from…
復讐だってばよ。
From revenge.
俺は　ぜってぇ　お前を→
I swear I'll save you from
the chaos of vengeance.
復讐の泥沼から助け出してやる。
フッ　そんな必要はない。
There's no need for that.
俺の復讐の幕は　すでに上がった。
The stage has already been set
for my vengeance to happen!
さっきだ。
Just awhile ago,
さっき　やっと１人だけ
イタチの仇を討てた。
I finally got to take revenge
on one of Itachi's enemies.
((その右腕を手に入れるために→
How many Uchiha did
you kill to get that right arm?!
何人のうちはを手にかけた！
（ダンゾウ）その手を下したのは　イタチだ。
It was Itachi who enabled me
to get it.
お前がそうさせた！
You made him do it!
《これは　裏四象封印術》
This is the Reverse
Tetragram Sealing Jutsu.
(サスケ！　ダンゾウから離れろ))
Sasuke!
Get away from Danzo!
木ノ葉の上役を　この場で殺した。
I killed a high-ranking elder
of the Hidden Leaf.
ダンゾウってヤツだ。
Someone named Danzo.
《あのダンゾウを→
Sasuke killed Danzo all by himself?
サスケが　たった一人で
倒したというのか？》
今までにない感覚だ。
I've never felt like this before.
I feel the tainted Uchiha name
becoming cleansed.
汚された　うちはが
浄化されていく感覚。
腐れきった忍世界から
うちはを決別させる感覚。
I feel the Uchiha getting free
from this rotting ninja world.
お前たちには　わかるはずもない。
You guys couldn't begin
to understand.
俺のやっていることは→
And isn't what I'm doing exactly
what you Leaf ninja wanted all along?
ある意味　お前たち木ノ葉が
ずっと望んできたことだ。
昔から　うちはを否定し続けた
お前たちの望みどおり→
You've always snubbed and
put down the Uchiha.
So I'll help erase the Uchiha
from your memories.
お前たちの記憶から
うちはを消してやる。
お前たちを…。
I'm going to kill all of you,
木ノ葉のすべてを→
and destroy the Hidden Leaf!
殺すことでな！
Severing all bonds to
the Hidden Leaf
木ノ葉との繋がりを
すべて断ち切ることこそが浄化。
is the ultimate purification!
それこそが本当の
うちは再興だ！
And that shall lead to
the Uchiha's true restoration!
サスケ君…。
Sasuke…
《憎しみ…
その積み重ねの歴史が→
Hatred. The history of repeated
accumulating hatred.
That is what created
the Sasuke in front of us.
今のサスケを作ってしまった。
サスケもその時代の
被害者なのだと→
Though they may not realize it,
Naruto and Sakura are
seeing with their own eyes
ナルトもサクラも→
that Sasuke is a victim
of the times we live in.
はっきりではないが
肌で感じている。
And that is why…
だからこそ…》
This is my task.
これは　俺の役目だ。
ナルト　サクラ　お前たちは
ここから消えろ。
Naruto, Sakura.
Get out of here.
カカシ先生　でも…。
But Kakashi Sensei…
ここにいれば　見たくないものを
見ることになる。
If you stay, you'll see things
you do not want to see.
今のうちに行け。
私は…。
Now go!
I…
サクラ　シズネに教わった
毒つきのクナイ程度じゃ→
Sakura, the poison-laced kunai
Shizune taught you how to use
won't kill Sasuke.
サスケは死なない。
大蛇丸に耐性を埋め込まれてる。
Orochimaru gave him
resistance to poisons.
それに
もう自分の気持がわかったろ。
What's more… You've come to terms
with your feelings, right?
（香燐）サスケ！
Sasuke… I healed you.
うちが回復させたとはいえ
アンタの体は…。
But your body cannot…
withstand another battle.
これ以上　戦うのはあかん…。
サスケ…。
Sasuke…
((動くな　香燐。
Don't move, Karin.
えっ！？
うっ！　急所を人質ごと。
A vital point…
Right through the hostage!
（マダラ）フッ　そうこなくては。
That's what I wanted to see.
(兄さん　まずは１人目だ))
Brother… One down.
《いや　もういいんだ
サスケのことは…》
No… I don't care about
Sasuke anymore.
カカシ先生
見たくないものを見るって→
Kakashi Sensei,
this "something" I don't want to see…
Are you going to kill Sasuke?
サスケを殺すってことか？
いけ　２人とも…。
Go! Both of you!
隙を生んだな　容赦はしない！
Now's my chance!
I'm not holding back!
待て　ナルト！
Wait, Naruto!
ナルト！
Naruto!
♪～
《もしかしたら　サスケ。
There's a chance, Sasuke…
俺とお前が→
that our roles…
逆だったかもしれねえ》
could have been reversed.
((イタチ：逃げて　逃げて
生にしがみつくがいい。
Run…keep running…
and cling to life.
そして　いつか
俺と同じ眼を持って→
Then one day,
come before me with
the same eye that I possess.
(俺の前に来い))
千鳥！
螺旋丸！
– Chidori!
– Rasengan!
サスケ　お前も知ってんだろ。
Sasuke… You remember, right?
俺が昔　里のみんなに
嫌われてたこと。
The entire village used
to despise me.
その理由ってのが
俺の中の九尾だ。
It's because I have
the Nine-Tails inside me.
俺も昔は
里のみんなを恨んでいた。
At one time, I hated the village too.
復讐してやろうと
思ったこともあるし。
I even thought about revenge.
I want you to wipe off
every bit of that graffiti!
((落書きが消えるまで
きれいに拭きとるんだぞ！
ほら　あの子　例のあれよ。
Look. It's that boy.
なんで　あんな子を
里に置いとくのかしら？
Why is he allowed to remain
in the village?
三代目も
考えてくれたらいいのにね。
I wish the Third Hokage
would reconsider.
Shut up!
うっせえ！
はぁ！
この野郎　あっち行け！
You brat! Go away!
いきなり何すんだってばよ！
What's the big idea?!
こんなもの！
Here!
テメエにくれてやるから
とっとと失せろ！
I'll give that to you
if you just leave.
何だよ　何でなんだよ？
Why? Why?!
Why does everyone,
even my homeroom teacher…
そうやって　みんな
俺のことを！
担任の先こうまでが
そんな目で見るんだ！
Why do you all look
at me like that?!
I'm not a nuisance and
I'm not some kind of germ!
俺は　迷惑でも
ばい菌でもねえってばよ！
(俺は…　俺は　うずまきナルトだ！))
I'm… I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
一歩間違えば　お前みたいに→
One step in the wrong direction
and I might have conjured up
some terrible plan just like you.
恐ろしいことまで
考えたかもしれねえ。
俺には誰とも
つながりなんてないと思ってた。
I used to think I didn't have
any bonds with anyone.
お前や　イルカ先生に会うまでは。
That's until I met you
and Iruka Sensei.
((コウジ　帰るよ！
Koji! Time to go home!
Daichi! Dinnertime!
ダイチ　夕飯だぞ！
ハーイ！
Okay.
みんな帰るわよ！
母ちゃん！
Let's go home, everyone.
Mom!
何やってんの！　あの子と遊んじゃ
ダメだって言ってんだろ！
What are you doing?
I told you not to play with that boy.
Come on, let's go!
(さあ　行くわよ))
((ナルト…
本当のことを教えてやるよ。
Naruto… I'll tell you the truth.
１２年前　化け狐を封印した事件は
知っているな？
You know about
the incident 12 years ago
when the fox spirit
was sealed, right?
それ以来　里には
ある掟が作られた。
Since then, there's been
a certain law in the village.
A certain law?
ある掟？
それは　お前だけには→
Well…
It's a law that you were
never supposed to know about.
決して知らされることのない
掟だった。
Only me?
Why is there such a law?
俺にだけ？
何なんだ　その掟って？
ナルトの正体が
化け狐だと口にしない掟だ。
It's a law that forbids
anyone from saying
that your true form
is the fox spirit.
つまり　お前が
イルカの両親を殺し→
里を壊滅させた
九尾の妖狐なんだよ。
お前は　憧れの４代目火影に
九尾を封印されたあげく→
里のみんなに
ずっと騙されていたんだよ！
お前なんか　誰も認めやしない！
死ね　ナルト！
わあ！
(（イルカ）ナルト　伏せろ！))
だけど…。
((そうだよな　ナルト
さみしかったんだよな。
苦しかったんだよな。
ごめんな　ナルト。
俺が
もっとしっかりしてりゃあ→
(こんな思いさせずにすんだのに))
ヤケになりそうだった俺を→
オメエや　イルカ先生が
助けてくれたんだ。
俺だって　いつもお前が
１人なのは知ってた。
お前の姿を見て→
同じようなヤツがいるって
安心してた。
俺も　お前も　まだガキで→
今になって思えば
俺は九尾　お前はうちはの宿命。
似たようなモン背負ってたなんて
皮肉だよな。
お前を見かけてたときだってよ。
本当は　すぐにでも
話しかけたかった。
なんか　嬉しくってよ。
お前なら　俺のことを
わかってくれるんじゃねえかって。
けど　それはやめた。
どうしてかっていうとよ→
何でもできるお前が
羨ましくって→
俺は勝手に
お前を俺のライバルに決めた。
あのときから
お前は俺の目標になったんだ。
（くもじい）もしもし
そこの　あなた。
たまには　空から日本を眺めてみる
というのは　どうじゃろう？
今回　わしらが飛ぶのは
東急田園都市線じゃ。
（くもみ）田園都市線？
たまプラーザや　あざみ野など→
オシャレな街が多い
奥様に人気のエリアじゃな。
すごい！
もちろん　住宅地の中にも
不思議なものが　いっぱいじゃ。